Guide to the Humphreys-Marvin-Olmstead Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MISCELLANEOUS, 1762-1856, undated; Series V; 4" (4/5 box)
  - Dwight Family MSS
    - Correspondence
      - Ely, J[ospeh?] M[erriman, b. 1788?]
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1815 March 24 (Box 7, Folder 282)
      - Morse, Jedidiah, 1761-1826
        - ALS to Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, 1803 August 30 (Box 7, Folder 283)
      - Silliman, Benjamin, 1779-1864
        - Electrostatic copy of record of the last wishes of Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817, in minutes of a conversation between him and Theodore Dwight, 1764-1846. [Original MS transferred to Benjamin Silliman Papers, Series III, Box 34A, folder 48A, Department of Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.], 1817 February 20 (Box 7, Folder 284)
    - Journals
      - [Dwight, Timothy, 1752-1817]
        - MS travel notebook entitled: "From Concord to Portsmouth No. 10." 48 leaves. One of 17 original numbers of Dwight's narrative of a "Journey to Berwick." Published in Volume I of his Travels in New England and New York (New Haven, 1821-1822), letters XXXVIII-XLI., [1796?] (Box 7, Folder 285)
        - Story of General Peleg Wadsworth, 1748-1830. 50 pp. Unidentified holograph, possibly that of Benjamin Woolsey Dwight, 1780-1850, with interlined corrections in hand of Timothy Dwight, 1752-1817. Early draft of part of Dwight's narrative of a "Journey to the White Mountains," published in Volume II of his Travels in New England and New York (New Haven, 1821-1822), letters XVIII XIX. [Cited by William D. Williamson in his... (2 vols., Hallowell, [Me.] 1832), II, 496, as "Narrative of General Wadsworth's imprisonment."], [post-1802?] (Box 7, Folder 285)
  - John Trumbull (1750-1831) MSS
    - Correspondence
      - Adams, John, 1735-1826
        - Copy of letter from John Trumbull, 1800 July (Box 7, Folder 287)
      - Burr, Aaron, 1756-1836
        - ALS to John Trumbull, 1792 August 20 (Box 7, Folder 288)
      - Converse, Sherman
        - ALS, with enclosure, to John Trumbull, 1826 March 1 (Box 7, Folder 289)
      - Deane, Silas, 1737-1789
        - 3 ALS to John Trumbull, 1775 May 12, November 15, undated (Box 7, Folder 290)
      - Howe, Rev. Joseph, 1746/7-1775
        - 4 ALS to John Trumbull, 1772 December 31, 1773 April 17, July 27, 1775 January 24 (Box 7, Folder 291)
        - 3 ALS from John Trumbull, 1773 March 17 July 13 1774 December 10 (Box 7, Folder 291)
      - Humphreys, David, 1752-1818
        - ALS from John Trumbull, 1782 April 7 (Box 7, Folder 292)
      - Webster, Noah, 1758-1843
        - 2 ALS to John Trumbull, 1825 October 20, 1829 December 24 (Box 7, Folder 293)
      - Williams, Ebenezer C., Jr., 1755-1777
        - ALS to John Trumbull, 1775 December 4 (Box 7, Folder 294)
      - Williams, Jon[athan, d. 1780?]
        - ALS to John Trumbull, 1775 March 8 (Box 7, Folder 295)
    - Writings
      - "Sketch of the Life and Character of the late Governor [Jonathan] Trumbull [1710-1785]. Written at the Request of his Family. By John Trumbull of Hartford. September 1809", [1809 Sep] (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Miscellaneous Autographs
    - Adams, John, 1735-1826
      - 4 letters to John Trumbull, 1750/1-1831 (transcripts), 1775 November 5, 1776 February [13], 1805 August 5, November 18 (Box 7, Folder 297)
    - Adams, John Quincy, 1767-1848
      - Letterpress copy of letter to Levett Harris, 1815 February 5 (Box 7, Folder 298)
    - Clay, H[enry], 1777-1852
      - ALS to _______, 1811 October 8 (Box 7, Folder 299)
    - Clinton, De Witt, 1769-1828
      - ALS to E[dmund] C[harles] Genet, 1763-1834, 1806 May 9 (Box 7, Folder 300)
    - [Genet, Edmond Charles, 1763-1834?]
      - Draft of letter to [De Witt Clinton?], 1806 May 4 (Box 7, Folder 301)
    - Pintard, John, 1759-1844
      - ALS to Fitch Hall, [1814] May 27 (Box 7, Folder 302)
    - Ryan, Samuel
      - ALS[?] to _______; Sheahan, enclosing eye-witness accounts by "Shannon" re: (1) The War at Sea in 1812; (2) The Engagement between the Shannon and the Chesapeake, 1856 April 8 (Box 7, Folder 303)
      - "Shannon" (pseudonym)
        See: box 7, folder 303
    - [Tabor, Elnathan]
      - Court order to the sherrif of County Bristol, Massachusetts, to attach the goods of William Nicholson, Jr., of Chatham, County Barnstable, on behalf of the estate of Elnathan Tabor, late of Dartmouth, County Bristol. Signed, Timothy Fales, 1762 May 24 (Box 7, Folder 304)
    - Washington, George, 1732-1799
      - Facsimile of letter to Francis Hopkinson, 1737-1791, 1785 May 16 (Box 7, Folder 305)
      - Facsimile of letter to James Madison, 1750/1-1836, 1792 May 20 (Box 7, Folder 305)
- Additional Material, 1796; Accession 1997-M-121
  Humphreys-Marvin-Olmsted Coll. - 72
  - "Report of Proceedings of D. Humphreys as Minister Resident at Lisbon," [Vol. IV], 1796. 1 (Box 1)